Dr Mark Warner, FHEA Lecturer in Information Security, University College London

Lecturer in UCL's Computer Science Department and part of the Information Security Research Group conducting interdisciplinary research at the intersection of human-computer interaction (HCI), online safety, and crime and policing. Mark was the computer science lead for OMDDAC, a UKRI funded observatory for monitoring data driven approaches to COVID-19 (omddac.org.uk), and the PI/Co-I on two UKRI (REPHRAIN) sub-award project developing proactive online harms intervention tools, and Co-I on a Google funded project researching user-centred privacy mechanisms in fertility tracking apps. In addition to this research, Mark is an expert advisor for the National Police Chiefs Council (NPCC) Vulnerability Knowledge and Practice Programme (VKPP), providing expert advice, consultation and ensuring scrutiny of the programmes research. He also acts as an expert on the Thames Valley Police data ethics committee providing guidance on the use of data-driven systems in policing to support decision-making. Prior to working in academia, Mark was a digital forensics engineer, conducting case-driven research primarily in the area of mobile device forensics.

EDUCATION

University College London (London, UK)

University of Portsmouth (Distance Learning, UK/UAE)

M.Sc. in Security Management | Institute of Criminal Justice

Sept 2014 – Aug 2016

WORK EXPERIENCE

University College London (London, UK)

Lecturer (Assistant Professor) | Computer Science

Sept 2022 – Present

Supervising undergraduate and postgraduate students on a range of project topics, including primary supervision of a PhD student (2nd year). Actively engaged in independent research on topics of online privacy, disclosure, security, and safety. The research is situated within the field of HCI utilising a range of research methods, including user surveys (included representative large scale), semi-structured interviews, inquiry interviews, diary studies, online experimental designs.

Northumbria University

Newcastle upon Tyne, UK

Visiting Researcher Computer and Information Sciences	Sept 2022 – Present
Assistant Professor Computer and Information Sciences	Sept 2019 – Sept 2022

Abu Dhabi Police Force

Abu Dhabi, UAE

Digital Forensics Consultant | Digital Forensics Laboratory June 2012 – Sept 2016

Metropolitan Police Service

London, UK

Forensics Engineer | Intelligence Bureau Oct 2008 – May 2012

Serious Fraud Office, Digital Forensics Unit (UK)

London, UK

Senor Forensics Engineer | Digital Forensics Unit Oct 2006 – Sept 2008

AWARDS

2020	CHI Conference Honourable Mention Paper Award
2016	UCL Faculty of Eng. Scholarship (Dean award)
2014 & 15	Two police commendations for excellence in project management.

AWARDED FUNDING

Awarded approximately £720,000 in research funding since 2019 across 5 grants

2022 Google Faculty Research Awards Program (Co-I, ~£91,000)

Usable in-app data deletion mechanisms around sensitive data in female health apps

2022 Google Faculty Research Awards Program (Co-I, \$75,000)

Usable in-app data deletion mechanisms around sensitive data in female health apps

2021 REPHRAIN Strategic Funding Call 1 (PI, £107,000)

Key2Kindness: An adaptive cross-platform "in the moment" hate speech detection and awareness mechanism

2020 Northumbria University Internal Competitive PhD Funding (PI, ~£60,000)

Exploring the relationship between family and health misinformation

2020 Arts and Humanities Research Council (Co-I, ~£400,000)

Observatory for Monitoring Data-Driven Approaches to COVID-19 (OMMDAC)

ABRIDGED PUBLICATIONS

h-index: 7 (Source: https://scholar.google.com/citations?hl=en&user=B2MxYPYAAAAJ) Total citations: 182 (since 2019)

- Scott, L., Coventry, L., Cecchinato, M., & Warner, M. (2023). "I figured her feeling a litle bit bad was worth it to not spread that kind of hate": Exploring how UK families discuss and challenge misinformation. In *The ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI)* (Vol. 2023). (A* Ranked)
- Patel, D., Pendse, S., De Choudhury, M., Dsane, S., Kruzan, K. P., Kumar, N., ... & Warner, M. (2022, November). Information-Seeking, Finding Identity: Exploring the Role of Online Health Information in Illness Experience. In Companion Publication of the 2022 Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (A Ranked)
- Warner, M., Lascau, L., Cox, A., Brumby, D., & Blandford, A. (2021, May). "Oops...": Mobile Message Deletion in Conversation Error and Regret Remediation. In *The ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI)* (Vol. 2021). (A* Ranked)
- Warner, M., Gutmann, A., Sasse, M.A. and Blandford, A., 2018. Privacy Unraveling Around Explicit HIV Status Disclosure Fields in the Online Geosocial Hookup App Grindr. *Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction*, 2(CSCW), pp.1-22. (A Ranked)
- Kitkowska, A., **Warner, M.,** Shulman, Y., Wästlund, E., & Martucci, L. A. (2020). Enhancing Privacy through the Visual Design of Privacy Notices: Exploring the Interplay of Curiosity, Control and Affect. In *Sixteenth Symposium on Usable Privacy and Security ({SOUPS} 2020)* (pp. 437-456). **(B Ranked)**
- Warner, M., Kitkowska, A., Gibbs, J., Maestre, J. and Blandford, A., 2020, April. Evaluating 'Prefer not to say' Around Sensitive Disclosures. In *The ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI)* (Vol. 2020). ACM. (A* Ranked)
- Warner, M., Maestre, J.F., Gibbs, J., Chung, C.F. and Blandford, A., 2019, May. Signal Appropriation of Explicit HIV Status Disclosure Fields in Sex-Social Apps used by Gay and Bisexual Men. In *Proceedings of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems* (pp. 1-15). (A* Ranked)

SERVICE (ABRIDGED)

- Member of the computer science department ethics committee
- Expert advisor on Thames Valley Police data ethics committee
- Co-organised a workshop at CSCW'18 on ethical and sustainable research, and at CSCW'22 on Information-Seeking, Finding Identity the Role of Online Health Information in Illness Experience
- Associate Chair (AC) for ACM CHI 2023, ACM CSCW 2021 & 2023, CHI LBW2019